<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>whitepaper on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/whitepaper.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in whitepaper on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 17:09:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/whitepaper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Summarization Systems</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/05/23/evaluating-summarization-systems.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 17:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/05/23/evaluating-summarization-systems.html</guid>
      <description>We’re excited for tomorrow’s online discussion about automatic text summarization! You can register here. During the event, Mohamed AlTantawy, CTO of Agolo, will explain the tech behind their summarization tool. In this blog post, he describes how his team evaluates the quality of summaries produced by their system. Join us tomorrow to learn more and ask questions about the approach! Evaluating the quality of algorithmically created summaries is a very hard task.</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/d879f22c1b7be3467b606c8aa8f7cfb6/tumblr_inline_o7n3a6bf5R1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Programming for Anomaly Detection</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/05/03/probabilistic-programming-for-anomaly-detection.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 14:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/05/03/probabilistic-programming-for-anomaly-detection.html</guid>
      <description>The Fast Forward Labs research team is developing our next prototype, which will demonstrate an application of probabilistic programming. Probabilistic programming languages are a set of high-level languages that lower the barrier to entry for Bayesian data analysis.
Bayesian data analysis is often seen as the best approach to machine learning. Models derived by this process are highly interpretable, in contrast to other modern models like neural networks and support vector machines.</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/1d842739c4ecb115ce586049dd552f48/tumblr_inline_o6kjvaPgBs1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Case for Machine Learning to Legal Departments</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/26/making-a-case-for-machine-learning-to-legal-departments.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 18:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/26/making-a-case-for-machine-learning-to-legal-departments.html</guid>
      <description>Since we released our text summarization resources, the legal technology community has shown interest in leveraging summarization technology to support litigation document review, deposition digests, and contract analysis. Data scientist interest to use machine learning to mine legal document corpuses and support legal strategy was also one factor motivating our summarization research. The time is therefore ripe for data scientists to apply new text analytics capabilities for legal use cases.</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/ebfd0ddb6284c50fde7a72b87f40462d/tumblr_inline_o69786Qw561ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Data Science Maturity</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/15/assessing-data-science-maturity.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 18:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/15/assessing-data-science-maturity.html</guid>
      <description>We’re getting excited for our Data Leadership Conference, which is set for April 28 in New York City! The conference will feature an expert panel where Haile Owusu (Mashable), Claudia Perlich (Dstillery), and Kirk Borne (Booz Allen Hamilton) will share practical insights on how to build data capabilities within complex organizations. We’ll discuss questions like: What skills should organizations combine in data science teams?Why should organizations invest in experiments that may fail?</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/f80852671283007961d228f73499ecc3/tumblr_inline_o5ornqRft01ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machines and Metaphors</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/02/16/machines-and-metaphors.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 16:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/02/16/machines-and-metaphors.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;703&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;376&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/2cf1b0924a1bfc66737d96f4797ef6f7/tumblr_inline_o2neravFOu1ta78fg_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;703&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;376&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;this-is-a-guest-post-by-a-hrefhttpwwwgenekogancomgene-kogana-an-artist-and-programmer-who-applies-emerging-technology-into-artistic-and-expressive-contexts-and-teaches-courses-and-workshops-on-topics-related-to-code-and-art&#34;&gt;This is a guest post by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.genekogan.com/&#34;&gt;Gene Kogan&lt;/a&gt;, an artist and programmer who applies emerging technology into artistic and expressive contexts, and teaches courses and workshops on topics related to code and art.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in deep learning research have renewed popular interest in machine intelligence. With new benchmarks set in tough problems (e.g., image classification and speech recognition), researchers are exploring unexpected and exciting applications, and eliciting public engagement and private investment. These recent breakthroughs have captured the attention of many for whom AI was previously obscure, as new capabilities spur applications of interest to wider public audiences.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But these advances have captured more than just our attention; they&amp;rsquo;ve captured our  imagination. Artists have been quick to apply these new techniques for novel creations, exploring the uncharted territories of machine creativity, slyly provoking questions of greater importance. What is creativity anyway? How do machines perceive, learn, and imitate?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/2cf1b0924a1bfc66737d96f4797ef6f7/tumblr_inline_o2neravFOu1ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Dog Is Enough: Using Hypernyms To Improve Neural Network Predictions</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/11/17/when-dog-is-enough-using-hypernyms-to-improve-neural-network-predictions.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 16:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/11/17/when-dog-is-enough-using-hypernyms-to-improve-neural-network-predictions.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Possibly true statement: the Fast Forward Labs dog is the cutest dog in the world. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;399&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;288&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/7df25fbff433a17f0a2d414666eff600/tumblr_inline_nxxgbxBEMd1ta78fg_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;399&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;288&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our General Counsel Ryan picked up the puppy a month ago and we’ve yet to name him. Ryan likes Renfield, which, as Bram Stoker fans know, evokes slightly different thoughts than “super cute,” particularly when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WaVZmo8CsGQ&#34;&gt;played by&lt;/a&gt; the ever-guttural Tom Waits. But the fact that we’re in no rush to name him tells us something about how we label and identify things. We know he’s a dog, we love him for his dogness, and thus far that’s been just fine. I personally tend to forget what breed he is, as my knowledge of dog breeds is shamefully sparse. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pictograph, in contrast, does an excellent job recognizing that our puppy is in fact a blenheim spaniel. Pictograph is the public app we built to illustrate how neural nets identify objects in images. &lt;a href=&#34;http://pictograph.us&#34;&gt;Try it&lt;/a&gt; on your personal Instagram feed!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;658&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;216&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/36ad21fb7fbc61e892ca66af5f684fe4/tumblr_inline_nxxgkiSgKa1ta78fg_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;658&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;216&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 97% confidence rate in the accuracy of the prediction is a dream for automated classification. Here, the confidence is so high for two reasons. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.image-net.org/&#34;&gt;ImageNet &lt;/a&gt;database used to train the Pictograph neural network has a lot of pictures of blenheim spaniels (971&amp;hellip;and yep, it’s prime). This labelled data informs the network what a correct classification &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; look like. The learning mechanism (called &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/09/24/how-do-neural-networks-learn.html&#34;&gt;backpropagation&lt;/a&gt;) then steps in and learns the network to predict the label “blenheim spaniel” when presented with new images that have similar features.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, the images in Ryan’s Instagram feed aren’t noisy. Note how the two images with 97% confidence rates show our puppy alone and facing the camera. This pose is similar to the stock images available on ImageNet, rendering it easier for the neural net to detect similarities. The confidence rate in the right-hand image including the human face drops to 62% because the data is noisier. It would likely drop further when presented an image of our puppy unconsciously playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ouroboros&#34;&gt;Ouroboros&lt;/a&gt; (the mythical snake that eats its own tail).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;462&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;328&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/bac3509687c5af7c21fd2fc853bf0501/tumblr_inline_nxxhlkZ4zi1ta78fg_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;462&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;328&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Instagram, like most data in the wild, rarely contains clean data that maps neatly to a model’s parameters or the stock photos in a training set like ImageNet. In turn, classification systems can yield confidence rates as low as 20% or 30% (or lower), generating doubts as to whether it’s worth using the technology at all. One way to improve unsatisfying results from a machine learning tool is to adopt a “&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-wtf-economy/artificial-intelligence-and-the-future-of-work-a0eaabea7c41&#34;&gt;human in the loop&lt;/a&gt;” approach, where humans step in and manually label images technology misclassifies or classifies with low confidence rates. But we decided to adopt a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/7df25fbff433a17f0a2d414666eff600/tumblr_inline_nxxgbxBEMd1ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Retail: Consumer Privacy Implications</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/09/29/machine-learning-in-retail-consumer-privacy-implications.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/09/29/machine-learning-in-retail-consumer-privacy-implications.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;1401&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;956&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/7404e8cb508c2bc469e5a9887f5ac5e4/tumblr_inline_nvgbviEbKS1ta78fg_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1401&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;956&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/08/19/machine-learning-applications-in-fashion-retail.html&#34;&gt;last retail post&lt;/a&gt;, we explained how emerging sensor technologies are changing data science for brick and mortar. Many companies are working to retro-fit physical stores with capabilities originally developed for ecommerce. Without adding any new sensors or tags, image recognition company &lt;a href=&#34;https://blippar.com/en/&#34;&gt;Blippar &lt;/a&gt;provides APIs that digitize physical products to create an in-app experience around them. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessoffashion.com/articles/bof-exclusive/farfetch-e-commerce-fashion-brands-omnichannel&#34;&gt;Farfetch&lt;/a&gt;, which initially brought an exclusive network of luxury brick &amp;amp; mortar shops online, recently announced that it will soon provide in-store analytics.&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In parallel, digital companies continue to seek out physical spaces to augment their customer experience. Warby Parker and Rent the Runway have physical stores, and Gilt and Etsy are exploring new models to engage consumers offline (Gilt has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://fashionista.com/2015/08/gilt-by-appointment&#34;&gt;private retail space&lt;/a&gt; in their corporate headquarters and Etsy &lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2015/08/25/etsy-squeezes-into-brick-and-mortar-stores-with-latest-shop-local-feature/&#34;&gt;launched an app&lt;/a&gt; to inform shoppers of sellers’ nearby products). These digital companies were built upon testing &lt;a href=&#34;http://pathtoperf.com/2015/04/07/01-with-lara-hogan.html&#34;&gt;every detail&lt;/a&gt; affecting their website performance. As tracking migrates to physical retail, it’s important that retailers consider the consumer experience risks associated with new technologies as they explore the benefits. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you look at something on the web, you get ads that pop up and follow you around - companies like that have much better advantage over brick-and-mortar retailers, and so they&amp;rsquo;re under more pressure to equalise the playing field.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/news/datablog/2013/oct/03/analytics-amazon-retailers-physical-cookies-high-street&#34;&gt;Kevin Kearns&lt;/a&gt;, ShopperTrak&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/7404e8cb508c2bc469e5a9887f5ac5e4/tumblr_inline_nvgbviEbKS1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Applications in Fashion Retail</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/08/19/machine-learning-applications-in-fashion-retail.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/08/19/machine-learning-applications-in-fashion-retail.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;1080&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;572&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/1ea7d218b3ec206decfb85436ead953d/tumblr_inline_ntcf1hms2i1ta78fg_540.jpg&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1080&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;572&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;this-is-the-first-of-two-articles-about-recent-developments-in-fashion-technology-part-two-will-focus-on-implications-for-consumer-privacy&#34;&gt;This is the first of two articles about recent developments in fashion technology. Part two will focus on implications for consumer privacy.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next frontier for recommender systems is the retail store. We’re used to associating machine learning with ecommerce giants like Gilt and Lyst, but can data science transform physical stores like Rebecca Minkoff and Zara? The impact would be significant, as more than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/pages/about-deloitte/articles/press-releases/digital-influences-in-retail-store-sales.html&#34;&gt;90% of retail sales still occur in brick-and-mortar stores&lt;/a&gt;, which could use data to redefine in-store personalization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The introduction of data collection in the retail space does not always require new tools; rather, retailers can gather granular data on customers and products by repurposing existing hardware like security cameras and clothing sensors in new ways. Developments in machine learning have made it possible to auto-process existing video feeds to track customers, from simple movement analytics to full body profiles. Smart mirrors, security cameras (CCTV) and radio-frequency identification (RFID) sensors which create rich datasets that make automated personalization in bricks &amp;amp; mortar scalable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/1ea7d218b3ec206decfb85436ead953d/tumblr_inline_ntcf1hms2i1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Now? Some Preconditions for Technology Innovations</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/08/14/why-now-some-preconditions-for-technology-innovations.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 18:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/08/14/why-now-some-preconditions-for-technology-innovations.html</guid>
      <description>We like to hold fast to the myth of the individual creative genius as the source of the world’s most impactful scientific revolutions or disruptive innovations. But it’s consoling to recall how Isaac Newton consoled his rival Robert Hooke: “If I’ve seen further than others, it was by standing on the shoulders of giants.”
 This is French how painter Nicolas Poussin represents Cedalion providing sight to the blind Orion, a mythological pair associated with each generation’s progress over its predecessors.</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/aedff218136a4dbddc112c09618503ae/tumblr_inline_nt365m6VoK1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Stirling Engines and Orchids: A Prelude to Deep Learning</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/08/07/on-stirling-engines-and-orchids-a-prelude-to-deep-learning.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 19:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/08/07/on-stirling-engines-and-orchids-a-prelude-to-deep-learning.html</guid>
      <description>Today’s post is inspired by a slow-motion recording we captured of a Stirling engine that Ryan, Fast Forward’s General Counsel, just so happened to have lying around our New York City offices. For the non-mechanics among us, a Stirling engine is a heat engine that operates by cyclic compression and expansion of air and other gas at different temperatures; the temperature differential translates heat into mechanical work. The slowmo in the video renders a hypnotic locomotive sound that differs greatly from the mechanic buzz of realtime.</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/1848a19b440d862d19082e450097910b/tumblr_inline_nsq7opgW3S1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
