<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>retailtech on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/retailtech.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in retailtech on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 17:44:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/retailtech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fashion Goes Deep: Data Science at Lyst</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/12/09/fashion-goes-deep-data-science-at-lyst.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/12/09/fashion-goes-deep-data-science-at-lyst.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;694&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;376&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/993f6c53159f5715d9c127b790bb4bf5/tumblr_inline_nz3b9rPB5w1ta78fg_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;694&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;376&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;On November 16, 2015, Lyst, an online fashion marketplace based in the United Kingdom, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/lyst-ad-campaign-fashion-meets-data-science-flavia-young&#34;&gt;launched its first advertising campaign&lt;/a&gt;. Featuring a series of ironic headlines (one simply says “Rip-off”) etched over beautiful images, the campaign emphasizes the company’s identity as a “challenger brand,” whose success “has been driven by marrying insights from data science with the emotional nature of fashion.” (CEO Chris Morton) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lyst.com&#34;&gt;Lyst&lt;/a&gt; provides fashion consumers with a central platform where they can mix and match millions of products from 11,500 different brands. In this context, data science serves as a virtual personal shopper, recommending products to users based upon insights from their behavior using the site. One might think these recommendations are powered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collaborative_filtering&#34;&gt;collaborative filtering&lt;/a&gt;, but the world of fashion is far too transient and fickle to support data models matching similar users. Matrices are sparse and inventory drains rapidly (consider flash sales sites like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gilt.com/&#34;&gt;Gilt&lt;/a&gt;). Instead, recommendation algorithms align consumer behavior with product features. And as the world of fashion is one dominated by image and appearance, fashion data science has a lot to do with image analysis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We interviewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ejlbell&#34;&gt;Eddie Bell&lt;/a&gt;, Lyst’s lead data scientist, about his team’s current efforts to use deep learning to analyze images and personalize recommendations to consumers. We talked about his past, his team’s present, and the fashion industry’s future. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Applications in Fashion Retail</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/08/19/machine-learning-applications-in-fashion-retail.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/08/19/machine-learning-applications-in-fashion-retail.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;1080&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;572&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/1ea7d218b3ec206decfb85436ead953d/tumblr_inline_ntcf1hms2i1ta78fg_540.jpg&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1080&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;572&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;this-is-the-first-of-two-articles-about-recent-developments-in-fashion-technology-part-two-will-focus-on-implications-for-consumer-privacy&#34;&gt;This is the first of two articles about recent developments in fashion technology. Part two will focus on implications for consumer privacy.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next frontier for recommender systems is the retail store. We’re used to associating machine learning with ecommerce giants like Gilt and Lyst, but can data science transform physical stores like Rebecca Minkoff and Zara? The impact would be significant, as more than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/pages/about-deloitte/articles/press-releases/digital-influences-in-retail-store-sales.html&#34;&gt;90% of retail sales still occur in brick-and-mortar stores&lt;/a&gt;, which could use data to redefine in-store personalization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The introduction of data collection in the retail space does not always require new tools; rather, retailers can gather granular data on customers and products by repurposing existing hardware like security cameras and clothing sensors in new ways. Developments in machine learning have made it possible to auto-process existing video feeds to track customers, from simple movement analytics to full body profiles. Smart mirrors, security cameras (CCTV) and radio-frequency identification (RFID) sensors which create rich datasets that make automated personalization in bricks &amp;amp; mortar scalable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
