<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>active learning on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/active-learning.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in active learning on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:41:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/active-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Learning in the Law</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/25/active-learning-in-the-law.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/25/active-learning-in-the-law.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;782&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;438&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/5419ce3290efb6634bdefc85748cbe2e/tumblr_inline_o67a1hhHOk1ta78fg_540.gif&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;782&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;438&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-nist-text-retrieval-conference-trec-logo&#34;&gt;The NIST Text Retrieval Conference (TREC) Logo&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/11/new-tools-to-summarize-text.html&#34;&gt;recently released research&lt;/a&gt; on neural network methods to summarize text. Systems like &lt;a href=&#34;http://fastforwardlabs.github.io/brief/&#34;&gt;Brief&lt;/a&gt;, our summarization prototype, are poised to modify how we consume text. Content systems were historically designed to help humans find, read, and research documents. But as electronically stored information continues to proliferate, systems will inevitably evolve to support research conducted by a man-machine partnership: machines will take the first pass to synthesize vast amounts of information, and humans will step in to derive more nuanced conclusions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One field where this man-machine partnership is increasingly important is electronic discovery (eDiscovery), the processes lawyers use to discover information relevant for litigation. The traditional model, where armies of associates and paralegals read documents to find relevant information, does not scale to contemporary information volumes. To promote efficiency and curb the exorbitant costs of review, judges have issued opinions permitting the use of software that automatically finds evidence (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.insidecounsel.com/2012/04/30/da-silva-moore-sets-stage-for-predictive-codings-a&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Da Silva Moore&lt;/i&gt; v. &lt;i&gt;Publicis Groupe&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and sometimes even requiring it (&lt;a href=&#34;https://e-discoveryteam.com/2012/10/25/news-flash-surprise-ruling-by-delaware-judge-orders-both-sides-to-use-predictive-coding/&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;EORHB Inc.&lt;/i&gt; v. &lt;i&gt;HOA Holdings LLC&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This shift in practice has created a large market for “technology-assisted review” (TAR) or “predictive coding” software. The industry is quite large, and vendors use TAR to refer to products that use rules-based Boolean logic as well as more advanced machine learning techniques. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But two voices in the space remain clear and constant. Since they met at the 2009 &lt;a href=&#34;http://trec.nist.gov/&#34;&gt;Text Retrieval Conference&lt;/a&gt; (TREC), &lt;a href=&#34;http://plg.uwaterloo.ca/~gvcormac/&#34;&gt;Gordon Cormack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wlrk.com/MRGrossman/&#34;&gt;Maura Grossman&lt;/a&gt; have &lt;a href=&#34;http://cormack.uwaterloo.ca/cormack/calstudy/&#34;&gt;published multiple papers&lt;/a&gt; demonstrating that continuous active learning (CAL) is the most accurate and effective technique to find “substantially all” relevant information in a document collection. As they write in their recent &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.practicallaw.com/w-001-8253&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Practical Law &lt;/i&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on the topic:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAL is a method for finding substantially all relevant information on a particular subject within a vast sea of electronically stored information (ESI). At the outset, CAL resembles a web search engine, presenting first the documents that are most likely to be of interest, followed by those that are somewhat less likely to be of interest. Unlike a typical search engine, however, CAL repeatedly refines its understanding about which of the remaining documents are most likely to be of interest, based on the user’s feedback regarding the documents already presented. CAL continues to present documents, learning from user feedback, until none of the documents presented are of interest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We met with Cormack and Grossman to learn more about why they believe CAL is the best approach for eDiscovery and how the landscape is evolving. Keep reading for highlights.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
