<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ethics on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/ethics.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in ethics on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 14:06:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Eli Pariser on the Ethics of Algorithmic Filtering</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/01/22/eli-pariser-on-the-ethics-of-algorithmic-filtering.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 14:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/01/22/eli-pariser-on-the-ethics-of-algorithmic-filtering.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;1442&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;1440&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/3172e6d87c1d99d12058845989f9041f/tumblr_inline_o1bgwg1jOS1ta78fg_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1442&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;1440&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chiefly his reflection, of which the portrait / Is the reflection, of which the portrait / Is the reflection once removed. / The glass chose to reflect only what he saw / Which was enough for his purpose: his image / Glazed, embalmed, projected at a 180-degree angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;-parmagiano-and-john-ashbery---self-portrait-in-a-convex-mirror&#34;&gt;— Parmagiano and John Ashbery - Self-Portrait in a Convex Mirror&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personalizing experiences and recommendations for consumers is the goal of many data science efforts, so much so that the NYC Media Lab created &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nycmedialab.org/personalizationpalooza-16/&#34;&gt;Personalizationpalooza&lt;/a&gt; to unite technicians and media leadership around the topic. And while &lt;a href=&#34;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1321962&#34;&gt;studies have shown&lt;/a&gt; that recommendation algorithms promote happy consumers, it’s questionable that also they promote healthy citizens.&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://technosociology.org/&#34;&gt;Zeynep Tufecki&lt;/a&gt;, for example, recently wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/message/how-facebook-s-tyranny-of-the-like-and-engagement-can-be-an-obstacle-to-an-open-and-connected-dddc03a0d39b#.2tc1yluvx&#34;&gt;Medium post &lt;/a&gt;explaining how Facebook’s focus on “engagement” as a metric for deciding which content to share on user news feeds can happen “to the detriment of the substantive experiences and interactions” she (and others) wants on Facebook. Zufecki illustrates her point with an instance where users felt morally unable to “like” a video with child refugees surrounded by dead bodies. She argues that the platform needs different mechanisms and metrics to ensure that content worth viewing can compete with the content we’re more apt to “like.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tufecki is not alone in her concerns. In 2011, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eli_Pariser&#34;&gt;Eli Pariser&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.upworthy.com/&#34;&gt;Upworthy&lt;/a&gt;, wrote the first monograph about the risks algorithmic filtering poses to citizenship and society. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Filter-Bubble-Personalized-Changing/dp/0143121235&#34;&gt;The Filter Bubble&lt;/a&gt; is still worth reading today, as it provides a framework for understanding how filtering algorithms work and what personal, social, and political consequences they may have. It’s critical we understand these tools now that the 2016 election season is in full swing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We recently interviewed Pariser to see how his thinking has evolved in light of recent algorithmic progress. Keep reading for highlights. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/3172e6d87c1d99d12058845989f9041f/tumblr_inline_o1bgwg1jOS1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
