<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>event on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/event.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in event on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 18:07:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Data Science Maturity</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/15/assessing-data-science-maturity.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 18:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/15/assessing-data-science-maturity.html</guid>
      <description>We’re getting excited for our Data Leadership Conference, which is set for April 28 in New York City! The conference will feature an expert panel where Haile Owusu (Mashable), Claudia Perlich (Dstillery), and Kirk Borne (Booz Allen Hamilton) will share practical insights on how to build data capabilities within complex organizations. We’ll discuss questions like: What skills should organizations combine in data science teams?Why should organizations invest in experiments that may fail?</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/f80852671283007961d228f73499ecc3/tumblr_inline_o5ornqRft01ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Do You Put Your Data Scientists?</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/06/where-do-you-put-your-data-scientists.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 15:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/06/where-do-you-put-your-data-scientists.html</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by Daniel Tunkelang, a data scientist and engineering executive, to preview the keynote he’ll deliver at our April 28 Data Leadership Conference in New York City! In 2012, Harvard Business Review proclaimed that &amp;ldquo;data scientist&amp;rdquo; was the sexiest job of the 21st century. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty amazing, considering that the job title was less than five years old at the time.
The Rapid Rise of Data Science DJ Patil and Jeff Hammerbacher, then at LinkedIn and Facebook, coined the term in 2008 to capture the intersection of analytics, engineering, and product skills that was becoming critical to their companies.</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/84ee6a02c04f8869d9b14bc31170c5d8/tumblr_inline_o57xvwb9QO1ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
