<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fashion tech on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/fashion-tech.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in fashion tech on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 12:37:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/fashion-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Machine Algorithms: Interview with Eric Colson</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/05/25/human-machine-algorithms-interview-with-eric-colson.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 12:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/05/25/human-machine-algorithms-interview-with-eric-colson.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;780&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;396&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/dd7cacb29c66b0d8ac385f37fde89d2d/tumblr_inline_o7qmpkkMD11qcg73w_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;780&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;396&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Therefore render unto Caesar the things that are Caesar&amp;rsquo;s, and unto God the things that are God&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;ndash-matthew-2221&#34;&gt;– Matthew, 22:21&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tend to think that recommender systems are old hat. ECommerce platforms like Amazon have been using techniques like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/How-does-Amazons-collaborative-filtering-recommendation-engine-work&#34;&gt;collaborative filtering&lt;/a&gt; for years to help shoppers navigate vast catalogues by inferring consumer taste from past behavior. And yet, we’ve all experienced the limitations of these approaches (that time you bought a toilet bowl plunger to subsequently be flooded by recommendations for strange bathroom accessories). This may be a nuisance for consumers, but it doesn’t jeopardize eCommerce business models: only 35% of Amazon’s sales, for example, are driven from recommendations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what would happen if the stakes were higher? What kind of algorithmic creativity would it take to build a company with revenue based entirely on recommendations?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the challenge faced by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ericcolson&#34;&gt;Eric Colson&lt;/a&gt;’s team at &lt;a href=&#34;http://multithreaded.stitchfix.com/&#34;&gt;Stitch Fix&lt;/a&gt;. Stitch Fix is an online “personal styling service” that selects clothing apparel for customers (they also have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://multithreaded.stitchfix.com/blog/&#34;&gt;solid technical blog&lt;/a&gt;). Instead of recommending items for shoppers to choose from, Stitch Fix goes a step further and simply ships items its algorithms and stylists choose to customers. The key to making this work, according to Colson, is to optimize the division of labor between human and machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Colson &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-rId42xabXY&#34;&gt;spoke about&lt;/a&gt; the value of human-machine collaborations at the March &lt;a href=&#34;http://datadrivennyc.com/&#34;&gt;Data Driven NYC Meetup&lt;/a&gt;. We interviewed him to learn more about the approach.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
