<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dimensionality on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/dimensionality.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in dimensionality on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 17:22:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/dimensionality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensionality Reduction and Intuition</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/12/08/dimensionality-reduction-and-intuition.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 17:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/12/08/dimensionality-reduction-and-intuition.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;651&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;513&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/a97d30b7577d5fb32955853cb2ec7b17/tumblr_inline_ohvie7chq81ta78fg_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;651&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;513&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I call our world Flatland, not because we call it so, but to make its nature clearer to you, my happy readers, who are privileged to live in Space.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So reads the first sentence of Edwin Abbott Abbott’s 1884 work of science fiction and social satire, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/201&#34;&gt;Flatland: A Romance of Many Dimensions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt; At the time, Abbott used contemporary developments in the fields of geometry and topology (he was a contemporary of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henri_Poincar%C3%A9&#34;&gt;Poincaré&lt;/a&gt;) to illustrate the rigid social hierarchies in Victorian England. A century later, with machine learning algorithms playing an increasingly prominent role in our daily lives, Abbott’s play on the conceptual leaps required to cross dimensions is relevant again. This time, however, the dimensionality shifts lie not between two human social classes, but between the domains of human reasoning and intuition and machine reasoning and computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the recent excitement around artificial intelligence stems from the fact that computers are newly able to process data historically too complex to analyze. At Fast Forward Labs, we’ve been excited by new capabilities to use computers to &lt;a href=&#34;http://pictograph.us&#34;&gt;perceive objects in images&lt;/a&gt;, extract the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fastforwardlabs.github.io/brief/&#34;&gt;most important sentences from long bodies of text&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.googleblog.com/2016/11/zero-shot-translation-with-googles.html&#34;&gt;translate between languages&lt;/a&gt;. But making complex data like images or text tractable for machines involves representing the data in high-dimensional vectors, long strings of numbers that encode the complexity of pixel clusters or relationships between words. The problem is these vectors become so large that it’s hard for humans to make sense of them: plotting them often requires a space of way more than the three dimensions we live in and perceive!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, machine learning techniques that entirely remove humans from the loop, like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.automl.org/&#34;&gt;automatic machine learning&lt;/a&gt; and unsupervised learning, are still active areas of research. For now, machines perform best when nudged by humans. And that means we need a way to reverse engineer the high-dimensionality vectors machines compute in back down to the two and three dimensional spaces our visual systems have evolved to make sense of. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What follows is a brief survey of some tools available to reduce and visualize high-dimensional data. Send us a note at contact@fastforwardlabs.com if you know of others!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
