<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>press on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/press.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in press on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 22:05:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/press/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What History Teaches Us About Data Science</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/02/03/what-history-teaches-us-about-data-science.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 22:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/02/03/what-history-teaches-us-about-data-science.html</guid>
      <description>The FFL team at the New York Historical Society&amp;rsquo;s Silicon City exhibit  Study the past if you would define the future. — Confucius
 Until April 17, 2016, the New York Historical Society is featuring an exhibition called Silicon City: Computer History Made in New York. The Fast Forward Labs team took a field trip to the museum back in December to augment our perspective on our current machine intelligence research (and, of course, to geek out and have fun).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flip the Paradigm</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/10/20/flip-the-paradigm.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 19:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/10/20/flip-the-paradigm.html</guid>
      <description>Last week, Hilary, Fast Forward Labs founder and CEO, gave the opening keynote at the Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing in Houston, TX. Her talk inspired an audience of over 12,000 women to embrace the unimaginable possibilities that will shape the careers of future technologists. Sure, aspiring engineers and data scientists have to endure the angst that they can no longer chart their future by emulating role models from their past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grace Hopper Opening Keynote</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/10/13/grace-hopper-opening-keynote.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 20:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/10/13/grace-hopper-opening-keynote.html</guid>
      <description>We’re super excited that our CEO &amp;amp; Founder, Hilary Mason, will deliver the opening keynote tomorrow at the Grace Hopper conference in Houston, TX. You can catch the keynote live at 9:30 EDT / 8:30 CDT on the conference livestream website. As a brief preview, Hilary’s talk will cover: how and why machine intelligence is revolutionizing computing; what today’s tech ecosystem looks like and how aspiring female technologists have to maneuver to succeed (be that landing the right job or starting a company); and how Fast Forward Labs is an example of a “hack” of the system, rethinking the future of applied research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Down Memes</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/10/06/breaking-down-memes.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 21:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/10/06/breaking-down-memes.html</guid>
      <description>Last week, Hilary spoke about opportunities for mid-sized companies to use data at Accelerating America’s Middle Market, hosted by the Wall Street Journal. This morning, I spoke about opportunities for large, established companies to use data at a Corporate Longevity Leadership Briefing, hosted by the Financial Times. Here are two key takeaways from the panels: Memes generate excitement; excitement generates hype; hype generates confusion. In her panel, Hilary aimed to demystify some of the sorcery surrounding ‘big data’ that risks rendering data projects intimidating to mid-sized companies with limited resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hilary on Bloomberg TV</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/04/30/hilary-on-bloomberg-tv.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 21:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/04/30/hilary-on-bloomberg-tv.html</guid>
      <description>Our fearless leader Hilary Mason appeared yesterday on Bloomberg TV to discuss Selerity’s early acquisition of Twitter’s earnings data. The interview video is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hoff</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/03/31/the-hoff.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 18:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/03/31/the-hoff.html</guid>
      <description>The Hoff stopped by Fast Forward Labs!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
