<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hedge funds on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/hedge-funds.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in hedge funds on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 16:18:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/hedge-funds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Economics: Interview with Jimi Crawford</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/08/24/next-economics-interview-with-jimi-crawford.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 16:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/08/24/next-economics-interview-with-jimi-crawford.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;656&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1629&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/de9fc93bc4bda585c1bb51a785fc7801/tumblr_inline_ocf6npUoHK1ta78fg_540.png&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;656&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1629&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;923&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;2291&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/e65b096c51449dd8ad7ef4b2f0e4ad10/tumblr_inline_ocf6k5SHv61ta78fg_540.png&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;923&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;2291&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;building-shadows-as-proxies-for-construction-rates-in-shanghai-photos-courtesy-of-orbital-insightdigital-globe&#34;&gt;Building shadows as proxies for construction rates in Shanghai. Photos courtesy of Orbital Insight/Digital Globe.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no small feat to commercialize new technologies that arise from scientific and academic research. The useful is a small subset of the possible, and the features technology users (let alone corporate buyers) care about rarely align with the problems researchers want to solve. But it’s immensely exciting when it works. When the phase transition is complete. When the general public starts to appreciate how a bunch of mathematics can impact their business, their lives, and their understanding of how the world works. It’s why the Fast Forward Labs team wakes up every day. It’s why we love what we do. It drives us. And it’s why we’re always on the lookout for people who are doing it well. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://orbitalinsight.com/&#34;&gt;Orbital Insight&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent example of a company that is successfully commercializing deep learning technologies. 2015 saw a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/12/11/science/an-advance-in-artificial-intelligence-rivals-human-vision-abilities.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;series of improvements&lt;/a&gt; in the performance of object recognition and computer vision systems. The technology is being applied across domains, to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enlitic.com/&#34;&gt;improve medical diagnosis&lt;/a&gt;, gain &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clarifai.com/&#34;&gt;brand insights&lt;/a&gt;, or update our &lt;a href=&#34;http://pictograph.us&#34;&gt;social media experience&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building on his experience at The Climate Corporation, Orbital Insight CEO  &amp;amp; Founder &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jmcrawfordjr&#34;&gt;Jimi Crawford&lt;/a&gt; decided to aim big and apply the latest in computer vision to satellite imagery. His team focused their first commercial offering on the financial services industry, honing their tools to count cars in parking lots to infer company performance and, transitively, stock market behavior. But hedge funds are just the beginning. Crawford’s long-term ambition (as that of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.featurex.ai/&#34;&gt;FeatureX&lt;/a&gt;) is to reform macroeconomics, to replace government reports with quantified observations about the physical world. &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/27/orbital-insight-lands-20-million-from-investors-led-by-gv/&#34;&gt;Investors have taken notice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We interviewed Jimi, discussing what he learned in the past, what he does in the present, and what he envisions for the future. Read on for highlights. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/de9fc93bc4bda585c1bb51a785fc7801/tumblr_inline_ocf6npUoHK1ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
