<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interview on Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/interview.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in interview on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 16:18:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Economics: Interview with Jimi Crawford</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/08/24/next-economics-interview-with-jimi-crawford.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 16:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/08/24/next-economics-interview-with-jimi-crawford.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;656&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1629&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/de9fc93bc4bda585c1bb51a785fc7801/tumblr_inline_ocf6npUoHK1ta78fg_540.png&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;656&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1629&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;923&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;2291&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/e65b096c51449dd8ad7ef4b2f0e4ad10/tumblr_inline_ocf6k5SHv61ta78fg_540.png&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;923&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;2291&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;building-shadows-as-proxies-for-construction-rates-in-shanghai-photos-courtesy-of-orbital-insightdigital-globe&#34;&gt;Building shadows as proxies for construction rates in Shanghai. Photos courtesy of Orbital Insight/Digital Globe.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no small feat to commercialize new technologies that arise from scientific and academic research. The useful is a small subset of the possible, and the features technology users (let alone corporate buyers) care about rarely align with the problems researchers want to solve. But it’s immensely exciting when it works. When the phase transition is complete. When the general public starts to appreciate how a bunch of mathematics can impact their business, their lives, and their understanding of how the world works. It’s why the Fast Forward Labs team wakes up every day. It’s why we love what we do. It drives us. And it’s why we’re always on the lookout for people who are doing it well. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://orbitalinsight.com/&#34;&gt;Orbital Insight&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent example of a company that is successfully commercializing deep learning technologies. 2015 saw a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/12/11/science/an-advance-in-artificial-intelligence-rivals-human-vision-abilities.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;series of improvements&lt;/a&gt; in the performance of object recognition and computer vision systems. The technology is being applied across domains, to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enlitic.com/&#34;&gt;improve medical diagnosis&lt;/a&gt;, gain &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clarifai.com/&#34;&gt;brand insights&lt;/a&gt;, or update our &lt;a href=&#34;http://pictograph.us&#34;&gt;social media experience&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building on his experience at The Climate Corporation, Orbital Insight CEO  &amp;amp; Founder &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jmcrawfordjr&#34;&gt;Jimi Crawford&lt;/a&gt; decided to aim big and apply the latest in computer vision to satellite imagery. His team focused their first commercial offering on the financial services industry, honing their tools to count cars in parking lots to infer company performance and, transitively, stock market behavior. But hedge funds are just the beginning. Crawford’s long-term ambition (as that of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.featurex.ai/&#34;&gt;FeatureX&lt;/a&gt;) is to reform macroeconomics, to replace government reports with quantified observations about the physical world. &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/27/orbital-insight-lands-20-million-from-investors-led-by-gv/&#34;&gt;Investors have taken notice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We interviewed Jimi, discussing what he learned in the past, what he does in the present, and what he envisions for the future. Read on for highlights. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/de9fc93bc4bda585c1bb51a785fc7801/tumblr_inline_ocf6npUoHK1ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Listening: Interview with Juan Pablo Bello</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/06/10/machine-listening-interview-with-juan-pablo-bello.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 14:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/06/10/machine-listening-interview-with-juan-pablo-bello.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;360&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;270&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/5cfcc6b830aa09f63bf9e9b2333524a1/tumblr_inline_o8k7rqJDmA1ta78fg_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;360&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;270&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-probabilistic-latent-component-analysis-of-a-pitch-class-sequence-for-the-beatles-good-day-sunshine-the-top-layer-shows-the-original-representation-time-vs-pitch-class-subsequent-layers-show-latent-components&#34;&gt;A probabilistic latent component analysis of a pitch class sequence for The Beatles’ Good Day Sunshine. The top layer shows the original representation (time vs pitch class). Subsequent layers show latent components.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is music? Or rather, what differentiates music from noise?&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you ask John Cage, “everything we do is music.” Forced to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JTEFKFiXSx4&#34;&gt;sit silently for 4’33”&lt;/a&gt;, we masters of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apophenia&#34;&gt;apophenia&lt;/a&gt; end up hearing music in noise (or just squirm in discomfort&amp;hellip;), perceiving order and meaning in sounds that normally escape notice. For Cage, music is in the ears of the listener. To study it is to study how we perceive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Cage wrote 4’33” at time when many artists were challenging inherited notions of art. Others, dating back to Pythagoras (who defined harmony in terms of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pythagorean_hammers#cite_note-8&#34;&gt;ratios and proportions&lt;/a&gt;), have defined music through the structural properties that make music &lt;i&gt;music, &lt;/i&gt;and separate different musical styles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The latest efforts to understand music lie in the field of machine listening, where researchers use computers to analyze audio data to identify meaning and structure in it like humans do. Some machine listening researchers analyze urban and environmental sounds, as at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wp.nyu.edu/sonyc/&#34;&gt;SONYC&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This August in NYC, researchers in machine listening and related fields will convene at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wp.nyu.edu/ismir2016/&#34;&gt;International Society for Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR) conference&lt;/a&gt;. The conference is of interest to anyone working in data or digital media, offering practical workshops and hackathons for the NYC data community. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We interviewed NYU Steinhardt Professor &lt;a href=&#34;http://steinhardt.nyu.edu/marl/people/bello&#34;&gt;Juan Pablo Bello&lt;/a&gt;, an organizer of ISMIR 2016 working in machine listening, to learn more about the conference and the latest developments in the field. Keep reading for highlights!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/5cfcc6b830aa09f63bf9e9b2333524a1/tumblr_inline_o8k7rqJDmA1ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome, Friederike!</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/06/02/welcome-friederike.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 13:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/06/02/welcome-friederike.html</guid>
      <description>Alongside our research on emerging machine learning techniques, Fast Forward Labs advises organizations on data science issues like technical architecture, new product development, models and algorithms, and even hiring the right talent. Our client base is growing fast, and we’re excited to support many large financial services, insurance, and media companies, as well as startups building cutting-edge AI products. We work closely with our clients to identify opportunities where they can apply our research and take our prototypes the next mile by implementing them on their own data.</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/48ec558f89fc83dbf3e1770639cf6404/tumblr_inline_o85byoZHrx1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Machine Algorithms: Interview with Eric Colson</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/05/25/human-machine-algorithms-interview-with-eric-colson.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 12:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/05/25/human-machine-algorithms-interview-with-eric-colson.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;780&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;396&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/dd7cacb29c66b0d8ac385f37fde89d2d/tumblr_inline_o7qmpkkMD11qcg73w_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;780&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;396&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Therefore render unto Caesar the things that are Caesar&amp;rsquo;s, and unto God the things that are God&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;ndash-matthew-2221&#34;&gt;– Matthew, 22:21&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tend to think that recommender systems are old hat. ECommerce platforms like Amazon have been using techniques like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/How-does-Amazons-collaborative-filtering-recommendation-engine-work&#34;&gt;collaborative filtering&lt;/a&gt; for years to help shoppers navigate vast catalogues by inferring consumer taste from past behavior. And yet, we’ve all experienced the limitations of these approaches (that time you bought a toilet bowl plunger to subsequently be flooded by recommendations for strange bathroom accessories). This may be a nuisance for consumers, but it doesn’t jeopardize eCommerce business models: only 35% of Amazon’s sales, for example, are driven from recommendations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what would happen if the stakes were higher? What kind of algorithmic creativity would it take to build a company with revenue based entirely on recommendations?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the challenge faced by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ericcolson&#34;&gt;Eric Colson&lt;/a&gt;’s team at &lt;a href=&#34;http://multithreaded.stitchfix.com/&#34;&gt;Stitch Fix&lt;/a&gt;. Stitch Fix is an online “personal styling service” that selects clothing apparel for customers (they also have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://multithreaded.stitchfix.com/blog/&#34;&gt;solid technical blog&lt;/a&gt;). Instead of recommending items for shoppers to choose from, Stitch Fix goes a step further and simply ships items its algorithms and stylists choose to customers. The key to making this work, according to Colson, is to optimize the division of labor between human and machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Colson &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-rId42xabXY&#34;&gt;spoke about&lt;/a&gt; the value of human-machine collaborations at the March &lt;a href=&#34;http://datadrivennyc.com/&#34;&gt;Data Driven NYC Meetup&lt;/a&gt;. We interviewed him to learn more about the approach.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/dd7cacb29c66b0d8ac385f37fde89d2d/tumblr_inline_o7qmpkkMD11qcg73w_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Learning in the Law</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/25/active-learning-in-the-law.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/25/active-learning-in-the-law.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;782&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;438&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/5419ce3290efb6634bdefc85748cbe2e/tumblr_inline_o67a1hhHOk1ta78fg_540.gif&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;782&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;438&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-nist-text-retrieval-conference-trec-logo&#34;&gt;The NIST Text Retrieval Conference (TREC) Logo&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/04/11/new-tools-to-summarize-text.html&#34;&gt;recently released research&lt;/a&gt; on neural network methods to summarize text. Systems like &lt;a href=&#34;http://fastforwardlabs.github.io/brief/&#34;&gt;Brief&lt;/a&gt;, our summarization prototype, are poised to modify how we consume text. Content systems were historically designed to help humans find, read, and research documents. But as electronically stored information continues to proliferate, systems will inevitably evolve to support research conducted by a man-machine partnership: machines will take the first pass to synthesize vast amounts of information, and humans will step in to derive more nuanced conclusions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One field where this man-machine partnership is increasingly important is electronic discovery (eDiscovery), the processes lawyers use to discover information relevant for litigation. The traditional model, where armies of associates and paralegals read documents to find relevant information, does not scale to contemporary information volumes. To promote efficiency and curb the exorbitant costs of review, judges have issued opinions permitting the use of software that automatically finds evidence (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.insidecounsel.com/2012/04/30/da-silva-moore-sets-stage-for-predictive-codings-a&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Da Silva Moore&lt;/i&gt; v. &lt;i&gt;Publicis Groupe&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and sometimes even requiring it (&lt;a href=&#34;https://e-discoveryteam.com/2012/10/25/news-flash-surprise-ruling-by-delaware-judge-orders-both-sides-to-use-predictive-coding/&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;EORHB Inc.&lt;/i&gt; v. &lt;i&gt;HOA Holdings LLC&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This shift in practice has created a large market for “technology-assisted review” (TAR) or “predictive coding” software. The industry is quite large, and vendors use TAR to refer to products that use rules-based Boolean logic as well as more advanced machine learning techniques. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But two voices in the space remain clear and constant. Since they met at the 2009 &lt;a href=&#34;http://trec.nist.gov/&#34;&gt;Text Retrieval Conference&lt;/a&gt; (TREC), &lt;a href=&#34;http://plg.uwaterloo.ca/~gvcormac/&#34;&gt;Gordon Cormack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wlrk.com/MRGrossman/&#34;&gt;Maura Grossman&lt;/a&gt; have &lt;a href=&#34;http://cormack.uwaterloo.ca/cormack/calstudy/&#34;&gt;published multiple papers&lt;/a&gt; demonstrating that continuous active learning (CAL) is the most accurate and effective technique to find “substantially all” relevant information in a document collection. As they write in their recent &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.practicallaw.com/w-001-8253&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Practical Law &lt;/i&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on the topic:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAL is a method for finding substantially all relevant information on a particular subject within a vast sea of electronically stored information (ESI). At the outset, CAL resembles a web search engine, presenting first the documents that are most likely to be of interest, followed by those that are somewhat less likely to be of interest. Unlike a typical search engine, however, CAL repeatedly refines its understanding about which of the remaining documents are most likely to be of interest, based on the user’s feedback regarding the documents already presented. CAL continues to present documents, learning from user feedback, until none of the documents presented are of interest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We met with Cormack and Grossman to learn more about why they believe CAL is the best approach for eDiscovery and how the landscape is evolving. Keep reading for highlights.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/5419ce3290efb6634bdefc85748cbe2e/tumblr_inline_o67a1hhHOk1ta78fg_540.gif</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shivon Zilis on the Machine Intelligence Landscape</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/03/30/shivon-zilis-on-the-machine-intelligence-landscape.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/03/30/shivon-zilis-on-the-machine-intelligence-landscape.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;727&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;541&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/74ea2d9c04837d672993d887788dcd76/tumblr_inline_o4tb0bi8wF1ta78fg_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;727&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;541&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;2016 is shaping up to be a big year for machine intelligence. Achievements like &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fdeepmind.com%2Falpha-go.html&amp;amp;t=OWFhNGUyZTg5YTZhMDA5YzMxMjhkZTcwZTA3ZjVkNTlkMTM5OWI5OCxXelB4R3dDVA%3D%3D&#34;&gt;DeepMind’s AlphaGo&lt;/a&gt; are making headlines in the popular press, large tech companies have started a “&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2016%2F03%2F26%2Ftechnology%2Fthe-race-is-on-to-control-artificial-intelligence-and-techs-future.html%3Faction%3Dclick%26contentCollection%3DTechnology%26module%3DRelatedCoverage%26region%3DEndOfArticle%26pgtype%3Darticle&amp;amp;t=NzFhYjEzNjJiMmY1NmNhZDFiMjQ2MWY0ZDQxYTc2MGUxODA2ZmZjNixXelB4R3dDVA%3D%3D&#34;&gt;platform war&lt;/a&gt;” to become the go-to company for A.I., and entrepreneurs are increasingly building machine learning products that have the potential to &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=http%3A%2F%2Ftechcrunch.com%2F2016%2F03%2F19%2Fhow-real-businesses-are-using-machine-learning%2F&amp;amp;t=MzRiYTE2MmVjYjBiN2UyZjQ3Zjc4YWRjOGI0ZjVmYmViODViZGY2OSxXelB4R3dDVA%3D%3D&#34;&gt;transform how companies operate&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exciting though the hype may be, the commercial potential of machine intelligence won’t be realized unless entrepreneurs and data scientists can clearly communicate the business value of new tools to non-technical executives. And the first step to communicating clearly is to define a vocabulary to think through what machine intelligence is, how the different algorithms work, and, most importantly, what practical benefits they can provide across verticals and industries. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.shivonzilis.com%2F&amp;amp;t=Y2UyNGUzNGI0YTMxYmNhYzFlNzQxMWJmMDMwZGI4YjBlN2ZmMTI3NCxXelB4R3dDVA%3D%3D&#34;&gt;Shivon Zilis&lt;/a&gt;, a partner and founding member of &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2FBloomberg_Beta&amp;amp;t=NTM4NjA1ZDJkZWU2M2FjZTgzNDk0Nzk0NzkwZDdlNjdiYWQwYjRkNCxXelB4R3dDVA%3D%3D&#34;&gt;Bloomberg Beta&lt;/a&gt;, is doing just that. She has spent the past few years focused exclusively on machine intelligence, building out a vocabulary and taxonomy to help the community understand activity in the field and communicate new developments clearly and effectively. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We interviewed Zilis to learn her views on the past, present, and future of machine intelligence. Keep reading for highlights!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/74ea2d9c04837d672993d887788dcd76/tumblr_inline_o4tb0bi8wF1ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeuralTalk with Kyle McDonald</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/02/18/neuraltalk-with-kyle-mcdonald.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 15:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/02/18/neuraltalk-with-kyle-mcdonald.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;640&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;427&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/806e99a04e9f647a198d0d887942562b/tumblr_inline_o2pgqgwhP01ta78fg_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;640&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;427&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;image-from-a-hrefhttpsvimeocom90547410social-soula-an-immersive-experience-of-being-inside-a-social-media-stream-by-a-hrefhttplauren-mccarthycomlauren-mccarthya-and-kyle-mcdonald&#34;&gt;Image from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/90547410&#34;&gt;Social Soul&lt;/a&gt;, an immersive experience of being inside a social media stream, by &lt;a href=&#34;http://lauren-mccarthy.com/&#34;&gt;Lauren McCarthy&lt;/a&gt; and Kyle McDonald&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, &lt;a href=&#34;http://siliconangle.tv/&#34;&gt;theCUBE&lt;/a&gt; stopped by the Fast Forward Labs offices to &lt;a href=&#34;http://siliconangle.tv/innovation-day-fast-forward-labs/&#34;&gt;interview us &lt;/a&gt;about our approach to innovation. In the interview, we highlighted that &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/02/16/machines-and-metaphors.html&#34;&gt;artists have an important role to play&lt;/a&gt; in shaping the future of machine intelligence. Unconstrained by market demands and product management requirements, artists are free to probe the potential of new technologies. And by optimizing for intuitive power or emotional resonance over theoretical accuracy or usability, they open channels to understand how machine intelligence is always, at its essence, a study of our own humanity.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One provocative artist exploring the creative potential of new machine learning tools is &lt;a href=&#34;http://kylemcdonald.net/&#34;&gt;Kyle McDonald&lt;/a&gt;. McDonald has seized the deep learning moment, undertaking projects that use neural networks to document a stroll down the Amsterdam canals, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@kcimc/comparing-artificial-artists-7d889428fce4#.ltnl33b5p&#34;&gt;recreate images&lt;/a&gt; in the style of famous painters, or challenge our awareness of what we hold to be reality. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We interviewed Kyle to understand how he understands his work. Keep reading for highlights:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/806e99a04e9f647a198d0d887942562b/tumblr_inline_o2pgqgwhP01ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What History Teaches Us About Data Science</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/02/03/what-history-teaches-us-about-data-science.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 22:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/02/03/what-history-teaches-us-about-data-science.html</guid>
      <description>The FFL team at the New York Historical Society&amp;rsquo;s Silicon City exhibit  Study the past if you would define the future. — Confucius
 Until April 17, 2016, the New York Historical Society is featuring an exhibition called Silicon City: Computer History Made in New York. The Fast Forward Labs team took a field trip to the museum back in December to augment our perspective on our current machine intelligence research (and, of course, to geek out and have fun).</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/45c6f3016da356bf6dc765883e601b93/tumblr_inline_o1zrwfo9mf1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eli Pariser on the Ethics of Algorithmic Filtering</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/01/22/eli-pariser-on-the-ethics-of-algorithmic-filtering.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 14:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2016/01/22/eli-pariser-on-the-ethics-of-algorithmic-filtering.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;1442&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;1440&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/3172e6d87c1d99d12058845989f9041f/tumblr_inline_o1bgwg1jOS1ta78fg_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1442&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;1440&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chiefly his reflection, of which the portrait / Is the reflection, of which the portrait / Is the reflection once removed. / The glass chose to reflect only what he saw / Which was enough for his purpose: his image / Glazed, embalmed, projected at a 180-degree angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;-parmagiano-and-john-ashbery---self-portrait-in-a-convex-mirror&#34;&gt;— Parmagiano and John Ashbery - Self-Portrait in a Convex Mirror&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personalizing experiences and recommendations for consumers is the goal of many data science efforts, so much so that the NYC Media Lab created &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nycmedialab.org/personalizationpalooza-16/&#34;&gt;Personalizationpalooza&lt;/a&gt; to unite technicians and media leadership around the topic. And while &lt;a href=&#34;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1321962&#34;&gt;studies have shown&lt;/a&gt; that recommendation algorithms promote happy consumers, it’s questionable that also they promote healthy citizens.&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://technosociology.org/&#34;&gt;Zeynep Tufecki&lt;/a&gt;, for example, recently wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/message/how-facebook-s-tyranny-of-the-like-and-engagement-can-be-an-obstacle-to-an-open-and-connected-dddc03a0d39b#.2tc1yluvx&#34;&gt;Medium post &lt;/a&gt;explaining how Facebook’s focus on “engagement” as a metric for deciding which content to share on user news feeds can happen “to the detriment of the substantive experiences and interactions” she (and others) wants on Facebook. Zufecki illustrates her point with an instance where users felt morally unable to “like” a video with child refugees surrounded by dead bodies. She argues that the platform needs different mechanisms and metrics to ensure that content worth viewing can compete with the content we’re more apt to “like.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tufecki is not alone in her concerns. In 2011, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eli_Pariser&#34;&gt;Eli Pariser&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.upworthy.com/&#34;&gt;Upworthy&lt;/a&gt;, wrote the first monograph about the risks algorithmic filtering poses to citizenship and society. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Filter-Bubble-Personalized-Changing/dp/0143121235&#34;&gt;The Filter Bubble&lt;/a&gt; is still worth reading today, as it provides a framework for understanding how filtering algorithms work and what personal, social, and political consequences they may have. It’s critical we understand these tools now that the 2016 election season is in full swing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We recently interviewed Pariser to see how his thinking has evolved in light of recent algorithmic progress. Keep reading for highlights. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/3172e6d87c1d99d12058845989f9041f/tumblr_inline_o1bgwg1jOS1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fashion Goes Deep: Data Science at Lyst</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/12/09/fashion-goes-deep-data-science-at-lyst.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/12/09/fashion-goes-deep-data-science-at-lyst.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;694&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;376&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/993f6c53159f5715d9c127b790bb4bf5/tumblr_inline_nz3b9rPB5w1ta78fg_540.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;694&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;376&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;On November 16, 2015, Lyst, an online fashion marketplace based in the United Kingdom, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/lyst-ad-campaign-fashion-meets-data-science-flavia-young&#34;&gt;launched its first advertising campaign&lt;/a&gt;. Featuring a series of ironic headlines (one simply says “Rip-off”) etched over beautiful images, the campaign emphasizes the company’s identity as a “challenger brand,” whose success “has been driven by marrying insights from data science with the emotional nature of fashion.” (CEO Chris Morton) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lyst.com&#34;&gt;Lyst&lt;/a&gt; provides fashion consumers with a central platform where they can mix and match millions of products from 11,500 different brands. In this context, data science serves as a virtual personal shopper, recommending products to users based upon insights from their behavior using the site. One might think these recommendations are powered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collaborative_filtering&#34;&gt;collaborative filtering&lt;/a&gt;, but the world of fashion is far too transient and fickle to support data models matching similar users. Matrices are sparse and inventory drains rapidly (consider flash sales sites like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gilt.com/&#34;&gt;Gilt&lt;/a&gt;). Instead, recommendation algorithms align consumer behavior with product features. And as the world of fashion is one dominated by image and appearance, fashion data science has a lot to do with image analysis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We interviewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ejlbell&#34;&gt;Eddie Bell&lt;/a&gt;, Lyst’s lead data scientist, about his team’s current efforts to use deep learning to analyze images and personalize recommendations to consumers. We talked about his past, his team’s present, and the fashion industry’s future. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/993f6c53159f5715d9c127b790bb4bf5/tumblr_inline_nz3b9rPB5w1ta78fg_540.png</imglink>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Pedro Domingos</title>
       
      <link>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/10/29/interview-with-pedro-domingos.html</link>
      
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fastforwardlabs.com/2015/10/29/interview-with-pedro-domingos.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure data-orig-width=&#34;1000&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;614&#34; class=&#34;tmblr-full&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://68.media.tumblr.com/4886047f032d47b832630a0ad0a72841/tumblr_inline_nwzgbcEPkQ1ta78fg_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; data-orig-width=&#34;1000&#34; data-orig-height=&#34;614&#34;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning technologies increasingly shape our sense of reality and the choices we make in our daily lives. They power Amazon’s product recommendations. They classify documents relevant for a lawsuit. They enable computers to play chess like the masters.&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As machine learning applications expand to influence our civic, professional and private lives, it’s important that we all have a basic understanding of how they work and what potential they offer. &lt;a href=&#34;https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~pedrod/&#34;&gt;Pedro Domingos&lt;/a&gt; undertook the challenge of providing the first comprehensive, nontechnical overview of machine learning in his new book, &lt;i&gt;The Master Algorithm&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;i&gt;The Master Algorithm, &lt;/i&gt;Domingos divides the field into five different “tribes” &amp;ndash; symbolism, connectionism (neural networks), evolutionary algorithms, Bayesian networks, and analogical reasoning &amp;ndash; which he challenges his readers to unify in one future “master algorithm” capable of learning nearly anything. This will towards universality informs his book’s bold central hypothesis: “all knowledge - past, present, and future - can be derived from data by a single, universal learning algorithm.” It’s up to us to find it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had the pleasure of interviewing Domingos last week. Keep reading to see the highlights. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <imglink>http://68.media.tumblr.com/4886047f032d47b832630a0ad0a72841/tumblr_inline_nwzgbcEPkQ1ta78fg_540.jpg</imglink>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
